# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 最近我们这里装了一个棚
We installed a canopy here recently
# 但是虽然说阳光也遮住了
Even though we are shaded
# 这哈子没得以前嫩晒的了哈
The sun is not as strong as before now, right
# 这哈子晒不到了
Yeah, it’s not too much sun now
# 就是上面的竹叶多得很
But there are a lot of bamboo leaves on the top
# 就是有一个问题竹叶老是掉到上面
There is a problem that the bamboo leaves always drop on the shed
# 才十多天你看
See, after only about ten days
# 就跟黑黢黢的样
It's already so dark
# 所以现在我们想办法把它弄下来
So now we are planning to clean it
# 我还特意买了一个梯子
I bought a ladder
# 买了一个这个铝合金的梯子
I bought this aluminum alloy ladder
# 本来是想借来用一下
I thought about just borrowing one to use once at first
# 我想到反正要经常打扫 就直接买了一个
And then I realized I always need to clean it, so I bought one
# 买这个花了好几百块钱
Spent a few hundred RMB on this
# 这样子扎实得多
This is more sturdy
# 帮我扶到哈嘛
Give me a hand
# 你上嘛
Go ahead
# 只是说它要横着跑 四伯爷你要注意到
It will slide sideways. Pay attention, uncle
# 横起跑不到
It can't slide sideways
# 你才好重点哦
You are so light
# 我还是有100多斤哈
I'm still over 100 jin
# 指到那个钢架桥上踩哦
You should step on those steel strips
# 上来了
I've climbed up
# 拿扫把上来是不
Bring a broom, right
# 啊
yes
# 不要朝两面滑就行了
Just don’t slide sideways
# 晓得
I know
# 干脆你们两个都上去整要快当点
Why don’t you both get up there to clean, that will be faster
# 我们两个上去整啥子哦
What can we do up there
# 我给你扶着
I’ll give you a hand
# 你怕还撑不起啊
Are you afraid of crashing?
# 不是的 这上面吓人得很
No, it’s so scary up here
# 有啥子吓人（腿）张开踩着2根条条（钢架）
Nothing to scare, just step wide on two strips (steel frame)
# 站起来都
I'm standing up
# 吓啥子嘛吓
Nothing to scare
# 开始扫了
I’ll begin to sweep
# 扫嘛扫
Just do it
# 二娃 这哈害不害怕哦
Erwa are you scared now
# 安
uh
# 这哈整了这么久不害怕了噻
You're not scared after all this time, right
# 这哈子不是很害怕了
I'm not so scared now
# 我们现在这个就搞好了
We now have done this
# 大家可以看一下我们这个梨树都结了果了
You guys can see that our pear tree is fruiting
# 这个梨子非常香
These pears smell very good
# 可以长很大
They can grow pretty big
# 但是如果不保护好的话 它这个鸟会来吃
But if we don’t protect them, birds will eat them
# 你看你这还套起得
Can you still hold it?
# 套是套起
Yes, I can
# 好好好
okay
# 我这哈把这里解了都
I’ll untie this
# 好多花花哦 小心点
Too many flowers, be careful
# 我们上去到上面去弄了
We’ve already cleaned up there
# 上面因为是有点半透明的特别吓人
It’s so scary because it is transparent up there
# 就是刚刚上去腿都会发抖
My legs were shaking when I just went up
# 但是走几圈之后就不害怕了
But it’s not scary when I have walked around for a bit
# 我们家这个梨树结了很多果
Our pear tree has fruited a lot of pears
# 可能再过三四个月吧 就可以吃了
They will be ready to eat, maybe after three or four months
# 特别的甜
They will be pretty sweet
# 四伯爷 这个梨子拿个口袋把它罩到哦
Uncle, we should protect the pears with some bags
# 可以安
Yeah, okay
# 二回来
Next time
# 这会儿还小个的嘛
They're still too small now
# 现在我们正好有这个棚
Now we have this canopy
# 到时候上去装那个袋子是很方便的
So it’s will be pretty convenient when we install the bags up there
# 嘎 很方便
Yes, very convenient
# 嗯 这哈就方便
Yeah, it’s pretty convenient right now
# 好 到时候我们摘梨子下来吃
Okay, we’ll pick some pears to eat then
# 不过要保护哈
But we should protect them
# 肯定要保护哈 不保护哈你弄不到吃安
Of course, you can’t get them to eat if you don’t protect
# 麻雀都要吃完
The sparrows will eat them up
# 好了 本期视频就到这里
Alright, that’s it for this video
# 到时候把梨子保护一下 有梨就可以吃了
Just protect the pears, then we'll have pears to eat